Good morning, welcome to campus, and I've met you to get up on the illness for so nice.
If you don't have a 20,000 students in traveling, I've never even seen it before I'm in the back
of the day every week of the day with your incredible kids, and I'm thrilled that you came here
this morning to watch our play.
If you didn't know you're having a play this morning, surprise, we're having a play.
And I can always guarantee you that it will be a little bit of a hot mess, but that's
okay, because the entire goal of doing these plays in school is that these kids get to spend
time together, that they get to make friends, that they get to be in this building as much
as possible.
When I was young in school, I spent so much time at our church, and you were all the best
running places, and in the rooms that were haunted, at least in my mind, like I loved going to
church, and I want that for your kids too.
So, the whole goal of this play is for them to get to know each other, to get to know each other,
but they're not going to have fun.
And you've already accomplished that, so no matter how it goes, it's fun.
You've already accomplished that again.
I want to thank you, Karen, so much for bringing your kids.
You totally didn't know this, but a lot of these kids have been practicing since October
for those speaking lessons.
And so, parents, thank you.
This is a crazy time of year for parents.
It's so hard.
There's so many things.
So, thanks for being a priority.
And I want to thank you and I'm Scott Morfitt.
I'm sounding the eyes because I don't know if you've been working.
I'm working extra.
It's going to make this happen.
So, some guys know that we were doing this, but it wasn't for them.
I also want to let you know that today shows our fourth week of events.
So, although the majority of the message will be on the playlist,
we do have a short, five-determinant message out through the playlist.
While they are going backstage to be teaching that we have hot traffic,
I'd like to talk to you a little bit about what Vince has been teaching me about joy,
because that is the topic that we're going to offer out of this.
And so, because of this, before we get started, I'm going to ask you to do a little exercise with me.
Number one, just everybody just wants to look at these ones because take in this moment.
Christmases, maybe this hasn't been the month that some of you thought it would be.
It's been fun, maybe it was, and even if it's not just the sheer volume of things that you have to do to get into this place.
So, I want you to just take a second and enjoy the fact that you're here,
and enjoy it at no one last place, because it goes by so fast with Jesus.
Now, I'm going to ask you to just close your eyes for a second.
I want you to draw to your mind the image of Jesus.
So, whatever that looks like for you.
It's not a test, but when you think of Jesus and respond of what really comes to your mind immediately.
I want you to start with that image, and then open up your eyes, and a question for you.
I want you to hear me, or when you pictured Jesus, was he's either laughing, or he's a big grin of his face.
So, you guys know you see what I want you to do, because of today.
So, honestly, for most of us, I was talking about this, we have this picture of Jesus where he's sort of like sullen,
even maybe he's really definitely not laughing, or he's in fact, even not saying that was a picture of my other minute time,
that I saw every year turning up, and so that's kind of the news that we've got.
But what I want to present with you today, also, is that we have been given an interest in the image of what Jesus was really like when he was here on this.
And think that his followers, the ones that surrounded him constantly, saw a different Jesus than what we've had in our lives.
What I want to suggest is that Jesus was actually the most, I think, joyful human being to ever walk this earth.
Not only that, but he was the greatest teacher of joy.
We often want joy, but we certainly don't look to Jesus for that happiness or joy.
We look to other things, but what I want to suggest is that we may not have been mistaken, and that Jesus is the best teacher of joy.
So, with all your worries, as we go throughout our place today, and stand for a friend for a little less,
I want you to look for glances of joy in Christmas stories.
And then we need to come back up and talk to you a little bit about what Jesus has been teaching me about today.
So, with that said, we are ready to go.
Ready?
Let's go.
This girl, this new hero, can be great things because I know what God has done for me for the baby born and death of me.
This girl, this new hero, can be great things.
This new hero, this new hero, can be great things.
This new hero, can be great things.
You can be great things.
This hero, can be great things.
Uh-huh.
Power of flight.
So I'm not sure about that one.
Invisibility.
Yes.
You're trying to lose yourself from this.
Oh, you've also needed to do that one before you're invisible off the base.
No, you're not.
And yes, you're saying that.
No.
It's not for children you're going to do to go right away.
I mean, they're trying to place me that nobody you notice me.
What do you want me to do?
I mean, I'm just a kid.
I'm just a kid who isn't special.
I don't post books.
I don't post videos.
And I don't consider what their sexuality is.
That's true.
But I have no one's birthday in nutrition either.
I'm a member.
I'm surprised how anybody would get notified.
But first, you can never use me what's that.
So I'm just trying to let you.
How do you love that?
Let's feel back to my children's activities tonight from the base.
Did you ever notice to go together with your sex on the table?
Oh, those are DOJs.
Like, I don't post them in every video because it's a lot of fun.
No, not those DOJs.
I mean, you guys have a lot of sex.
And I'll just look up again.
It's just this one.
Oh, those guys.
Is that why you have sex around them?
That's just it.
Exactly.
Or is one of those guys in the vicinity, too?
I'm going to go to the next one.
No, you're not.
What?
You're not the only one who can save the world.
As a matter of fact, there's only one who can save the whole world.
And you've got to be done.
Well, I'm going to go to the next one.
I'm going to go to the next one.
The word joy that he says is for all people just at the burst of Jesus.
comes from the Greek word chare.
It means an inner feeling of gladness or delight.
So whenever people say, I want my life to be blessed,
they don't experience that.
They want an inner feeling of gladness or delight.
And that's just from the birth of Jesus,
before he even starts preaching.
So then you look at the life of Jesus.
This is cool.
So we often, it's just, I don't know how it seems like so long and exciting.
But if you look at Scripture, it's not a lot of what he says.
First of all, Jesus, everywhere I went was feeling good.
Have you ever been there when somebody who had a diagnosis that was terminal is healed?
If the doctor comes to them and he says, I don't know how it explains,
but your cancer is gone and you're no longer terminal.
The joy that you feel that this family feels in this moment is like indescribable.
And Jesus said this everywhere he was.
People who have never seen.
He was not being able to touch their family.
I can't imagine.
Now being able to touch my family.
Knowing that you were going to go anywhere near them.
Those people were healed and then were able to hug their loved ones.
The joy that Jesus brought to those people, over and over and over again, was perfect.
Again, this was a hopeless and spiritual person.
And then you have the fact that children loved him.
Children are such a fantastic situation.
They are nothing that you're not a God that's like really sad and so loving when you're in heaven.
If you have a hard time getting children to hang around with you, that's a little bit more joyful.
And there was kids.
Children loved him.
Everybody knew what he was followed by kids.
The disciples and the Pharisees told children the best off of him.
And Jesus said, ask them, do not.
Bring the children to me.
Actually, if you don't come to heaven in the midst of a child, then you're missing it.
So children loved him.
And then finally, there's so many more examples.
But Jesus loved to eat.
He loved to eat.
There was a commentator on the book of Luke and they said, if you read Luke and don't get hungry, you're not really afraid.
Jesus was either on his way to a meal, eating or leaving a meal, almost throughout the entire gospel.
He loved food.
He loved to eat.
He loved to eat with those that nobody else wanted to eat with.
Because he loved them all equally.
You even look at the last supper.
He knew what was coming.
I don't think he didn't get bread, did he?
But I didn't know this.
I'm not wanting to do this.
He knew what was coming.
The last supper wasn't bread and carrots.
No, I'm sorry.
It wasn't carrots and water.
It was bread and wine.
Eating the last meal, Jesus did right.
He knew how to have a feast.
There's actually a book about this.
About the stuff that we often get wrong in Jesus' joke.
It's written by a man named Elton Trueblood.
And the book is called The Terror of Christ.
The subtitle is a bold challenge to the traditional stereotype of a somewhat somber, moony text.
So, he goes throughout this book and he gives examples of things that would have been really funny and like sarcastic that Jesus says.
One example is when Jesus says that it's easier for an animal to walk through in one minute and say, "Which man to enter the kingdom of heaven?"
For us, we'd take a look at the kingdom of heaven.
But we'd take a look at the kingdom of heaven.
We'd take a look at the kingdom of heaven.
And we'd take a look at the kingdom of heaven.
That's not what Jesus did.
And that's not what he's asking us to do as praise followers.
But what he's asking us to do is to look at everything that happens to you in your life
in the way of divine and sovereignty.
Knowing this is not eternal what you're going through.
You, the present, in the way of eternity.
Have you ever thought about that?
Whatever you're going through, what will this mean to you in eternity?
How much concern for this problem?
Again, you don't pretend that things are bad.
You don't know how many things are happening.
It's also looking at it differently than the rest of the world.
What will this look like in eternity?
Because the reality is, sorrow, the kingdom of heaven is temporary.
Joy will be eternal.
However, suffering is inevitable, right?
The Bible tells us, in this world you will have trouble.
Take one of those who come to the world.
It was nice.
The reality is, it doesn't come out of freedom.
The first time is word for people.
It's hard.
When things get thrown up and you want to lose it, and you just want to be angry and sad or depressed, it's not easy.
Actually, you're ready for this I'm going to quote Bono on Christmas Eve.
Bono, from YouTube, is quoted in saying, "Joy isn't asking defiance."
So, if you're one of those people that really likes to, like, go against the dreams, I've got those friends used for you.
This morning's message is for you.
And I've enjoyed it.
It's an act of defiance.
It doesn't make any sense.
Everything wants to be said.
When you say things that you turn on, anything commodity is off of our fear.
It makes money off of our families.
They need you to feel that fear.
So, to have joy in the midst of that goes against everything that you need on the cost.
And it's not easy.
So, I was sharing my message with Pastor Ray.
He was giving me a quote.
It was too good not to share with you today.
We already gave you tonight when you come back to our Christmas Eve service.
But it's so good.
You need to hear it twice.
So, this is a quote from Tim Donbass.
It says, "The task of the believer, therefore, is to live fully and truthfully into the reality of this world.
It's beautiful, but it's broken.
God has triumphed, but we still win his final victory.
We have been saved and restored, but we still experience pain, loss, and death.
We cannot deny any aspect of our reality, either negative or positive.
In fact, in a sense of brokenness, we relate, we grieve, and we mourn.
Yet, we celebrate, because we are God's people, and rejoicing in Christ and defiance.
It's like you have to go against what the Lord tells you to do, and you have to trust Jordan, like Jesus called for it, even though he knew.
Ultimately, every single person that he was speaking to, and that he was witnessing to would bring you and crucify him in the most horrific death possible.
Yet, somehow, he still loves them and have a joke on his way.
So, enjoy the end of a few things for you to figure out as you hopefully start your joy experience to become a joyful, happy person.
Number one, set your mind on joy.
You have to wait.
Because once you sit in the mind of yourself, I intend to be joyful.
In this moment, when I keep spilled his milk, he is a disaster.
God wants me to be joyful, because it's going to be cleaned in tomorrow, and I need to clean on it.
You have to see your pocket.
For you to be cleaned on the other things to happen.
And then he seems to have joy.
Tomorrow morning, Christmas, you must be going away with it.
It never does.
All the presents that you've asked are going to be open and sleep.
Although, put out your house, it's going to be a disaster.
Your kids are going to be bored 15 minutes after opening night.
Sorry, this is depressing.
Merry Christmas.
But it's true.
And we all have this idea of how it's going to go, and you know if it ever goes the way we think it is.
I know some of you are not having a Christmas in your life.
I know some of you are deep in the face of mourning.
And I'm not telling you not to mourn.
That would be innocent.
It means it's crazy when everybody's dying.
He knows what it's like to lose.
But, he still gets up, and he's a taste of your joy.
And you really don't just pray.
It's a real thing.
Eternity.
He walks more than he wants to lose or create.
The second thing is surrender the elimination of control.
One of my favorite pastors that I read is Tim Keller.
And Tim Keller is, I was talking to John Cooper before he died.
And he said, "One thing that I keep thinking of is," this Scripture verse where it says,
"Rejoice that your names are written in heaven."
That's the only thing he has control of.
Is, "You do make that moment in your life so you decide to follow Christ."
If you do it, your name is earth and heaven.
That's the only thing he has control of.
I'm free.
We have to stop believing the illusion that we are going to play.
I'm preaching to myself.
I'm in this control freak.
And now everyone wants to let it go.
It's not going to go to the reason it takes.
If you think it's going to go a certain way, it's going to feel I do it.
If you expect it to be not the way it's going to live, you can have joy when things
that are going right.
Third, these days constantly.
When you wake up in the morning, this comes for three days.
Every.
Single.
Morning.
It will start your day thinking about joy rather than thinking about everything that
goes wrong.
And then finally, focus your attention on all that's good.
Okay.
In Philippians 4:8-9, it says, "Find me, brothers and sisters, whatever is true, whatever
is noble, whatever is right, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is immonderable,
if anything is a biblical praise lady, think about such things.
Whatever you have learned or received or heard from me or seen and read, put it in practice
and that God is peace will be with you."
Again, this is not what we are afraid of every day.
We are not afraid of things that are joyful and peaceful and immorable and pure and right.
We have to go against the society's actions and think about these things.
It's why the Bible tells us to do it.
Otherwise, we will lose our joy over and over and over.
So, trade those thoughts.
Trade the negative thoughts for the positive thoughts.
Because what you give your attention to is what you will be encouraged.
Finally, take care of yourself.
Keep in mind.
I'm going to not have fun for you to be ready, but I'm tired.
Go to bed with early and eat good food with tips and sides.
And then we have to do those things so that we are mentally prepared to go against the ground
and have joy.
And then finally today, I just want to leave you with one more thought.
A lot of us are going to be sad.
Like, how many of you are going to use some sort of GPS to get where you need to go?
So, a month this year ago, I was in Patelman.
I was trying to get to the Patelman for my mom.
And the traffic was insane.
Because I'm crazy.
And I'm still in Chris was crazy.
It was all that traffic.
And of course, I missed the time.
And I was so frustrated because I had a very short amount of time and a lot of things I needed to do.
And I was so mad at myself.
But my GPS did not panic.
He calmly said, "Recalculating."
And then took me on a different path.
It wasn't the path I thought I was going to go on.
It took a little bit longer.
But he never freaked out.
I want you to think about that every single time you turn on your GPS and miss a target.
Are you reacting to the troubles that you do with your GPS with?
If not, if you're not recalculating what you made up like this together, then your house is moving on this gesture.
But the whole point of hearing that I'm going to do to you.
Two.
One.
This is in the direction.
I thought I already did.
And then took me.
We're just recalculating.
And we're going to get a little different direction.
And let God, please enjoy speaking to you.
Because after all, if Jesus was the most perfect person to overlook us and we are His apprentice, then we are called to live at life for joy.
And I know how hard it can be sometimes.
And that's all.
That's all for you this morning.
Will you please pray for me?
Please pray for me.
Please pray with me before we go start the rest of our Christmas Eve.